<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Book of the Fallen - Custom Armors</name>
		<description>
		Contains Custom Armors created specifically for the campaign &quot;Book of the Fallen&quot;.
		</description>
		<update version="1.0.5">
			<file name="botf-custom-armors.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/EliasKokkinos/umbraxakar/master/core/armors.xml"/>
		</update>
	</info>

	<!--Start:: Custom Armors for Book of the fallen -->
	<element name="Shield of the Umbraxakar" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_SHIELD_OF_THE_UMBRAXAKAR">
		<description>
			<p>The shield is emblazoned with a strange depection of a slender crowned woman, possibly a half elf, with golden hair, encompassed by two skulls of some type of beast. The image is engraved and inlayed with golden leaf.</p>
			<p>While holding this shield, you have:</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<ul>
					<li>Advantage on initiative rolls</li>
					<li>Wisdom (Perception) checks.</li>
					<li>When the bearer is reduced to bellow 20 HP he may be healed with Proficiency Bonus x d12 HP on a raw d20 roll of 15 and above. During this effect the woman on the shield opens her eyes and golden streams of Magical Energy surround the bearer.</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shield</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_INITIATIVE_ADVANTAGE"/>
			<stat name="perception:passive" value="5" bonus="advantage"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Tiara of the Mindmaster Matriarch" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_TIARA_OF_THE_MINDMASTER_MATRIARCH">
		<description>
			<p>While wearing this Tiara, you can use an action to cast the<b><i>Telepathic Bond</i></b>(amended) spell from it.</p>
			<p>In addition, you can use an action to cast the<b><i>Dominate Person</i></b>spell using your spell save DC from it. On a failed save, a creature is affected by the spell for the duration, and for the next 24 hours after the spell ends, you have advantage on Charisma checks you make to interact with it. These effects end early if you or an ally deals damage to the creature. If the target is connected to you through your telepathic bond, it has disadvantage on the saving throw to resist this spell's effects when cast in this way. Once this property has been used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_RARYS_TELEPATHIC_BOND"/>
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON"/>
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">tiara</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Mask of the Duke" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_MASK_OF_THE_DUKE">
		<description>
			<p>This skull mask covers the top of your face and offers several benefits while worn. The mask has 5 charges and regains all expended charges daily at dusk. While wearing the mask, you can use an action to expend 1 of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it (save DC 16):
				<ul>
					<li>Bestow Curse</li>
					<li>Fear</li>
					<li>Speak with Dead</li>
					<li>Tongues</li>
				</ul>
			You have advantage on Constitution saving throws you make in order to maintain Concentration on a spell you cast this way. In addition, you can read all writing.			</p>
			<p><br/><strong>Curse:</strong>When you place this mask over your face for the first time, make a DC 16 Intelligence saving throw. On a success, you are aware of the curse’s effects and can immediately remove the mask before it extends the curse to you. On a failure, you take 5d10 psychic damage as the curse extends to you and magically latches onto your face. As long as you remain cursed, the mask can’t be removed unless targeted by the remove curse spell, and the skin surrounding the mask is riddled with blackened veins and sickly gray skin. While wearing this mask, you can’t smell or taste anything and automatically fail any check relying on smell or taste. Your voice also changes. Use the table below to determine the new voice. In addition, whenever you roll a 1 on an ability check, saving throw, or attack roll, you take 1d10 psychic damage.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d6</td><td>Change to your Voice</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>Your voice deepens and doesn't echo</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>Your voice becomes raspy and overly enunciates consonant sounds</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>Your voice becomes quiet, almost a whisper, but can still be heard as if it were spoken at a normal volume</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Your voice becomes high pitched, and your laugh maniacal</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>Your words become slurred, as if your tongue is suddenly too large for your mouth, and your spit releases a faint hiss when it escapes your mouth</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>Your voice becomes that of another ally’s and changes each time you finish a long rest</td></tr>
			</table>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE"/>
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR"/>
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD"/>
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES"/>
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">mask</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE"/>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR"/>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD"/>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Armor of the Duke (Nobility Plate)" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_OF_THE_DUKE_NOBILITY_PLATE">
		<description>
			<p>This Plate dark armor has been made from nobility steel.<br/>
			Steeped in the blood from relentless battles, this metal carries with it a magical aversion to all things holy. While wearing this armor, you gain:
				<ul>
					<li>+2 bonus to your AC.</li>
					<li>Resistance to Radiant damage.</li>
					<li>The following benefits:</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p><b><i>Death Transference:</i></b>Whenever you are subjected to Necrotic damage, you can use your reaction to take no damage and instead gain a number of temporary hit points equal to half the necrotic damage dealt.<br/>
			This property of the armor can't be used again until the next dusk.			</p>
			<p><b><i>The Battlefield Remembers:</i></b>You can use an action to touch a weapon, piece of armor, or similar object that's seen blood and battle to recreate the effect of the<i>Legend Lore</i>spell, using the touched object as the subject of the effect. Once this property of the armor has been used, it can't be used again until 7 days have passed.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEGEND_LORE"/>
			</div>
			<p><b><i>Unholy Aura:</i></b>As a bonus action, you can speak the armor's command word to surround yourself with an aura of grim blasphemy. The aura remains for 1 minute or until you are incapacitated or die. For the duration, celestials have disadvantage on attack rolls against you, and the first time that a celestial moves within 5 feet of you on its turn or starts its turn there, that creature takes 1d10 necrotic damage. This damage ignores resistance and immunity. In addition, once before the aura ends, if you fail a saving throw against an effect from a celestial (such as a solar's Slaying Longbow}, you can choose to succeed instead. Once the aura ends, it can't be used again until the next dusk.</p>
			<p><b><i>Spells:</i></b>You can use an action to cast one of the following spells (save DC 17) from the armor:<i>Bestow Curse</i>,<i>Divine Word</i>, or<i>Nondetection</i>. Once the armor has been used to cast a spell, it can't be used to cast that spell again until the next dusk.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE"/>
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINE_WORD"/>
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION"/>
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">armor, duke, nobility, plate</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
			<set name="type" addition="plate">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="armor">Plate</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:armored:enhancement" value="2" bonus="enhancement"/>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_RADIANT"/>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEGEND_LORE"/>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE"/>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINE_WORD"/>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Plate Armor of Eloquence" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_HEAVY_PLATE_OF_ELOQUENCE">
		<description>
			<p>While wearing this Mithral Plate Armor, you gain the following benefits:
				<ul>
					<li>+2 bonus to your AC.</li>
					<li>The feat "Silver-Tongued (Persuasion)", i.e. +1 Charisma, Proficiency in "Persuasion", distracting attack action.</li>
					<li>The armor can be magically donned on/off in 1 Action using the command word.</li>
				</ul></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">plate</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
			<set name="type" addition="plate">Armor</set>
			<set name="armor">Plate</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="armorClass">18</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_PLATE</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:armored:enhancement" value="2" bonus="enhancement"/>
			<grant type="Feat" id="ID_BOTF_FEAT_SILVERTONGUED_PERSUASION"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Nightfall (Cape)" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_NIGHTFALL_CAPE">
		<description>
			<p>The cape latches itself seamlessly onto any type of armour. It is made from a dark cloth that even most experts would be unable to identify, but a true scholar would be able to trace its origins to the Eternal City.</p>
			<p>While being attuned to the cape you have resistance to chaos damage.<br />
			When attuned it absorbs any type of light around it and envelops the wearer in a 10 foot radius sphere of <b>Dim</b>, Kurald Galain darkness. When its command word is used, this effect becomes more pronounced and the wearer is enveloped in total darkness. The effect area remains the same.</p>
			<p><ul>
				<li>Can be dispelled only by certain Chaos Magic and the wearer loses the attunement if it's torn from the armour. Tearing the cape only un-attunes and does not damage the cape in any way. Tearing the cape works the same way as disarming.</li>
				<li>During the identification/attunement process the person is made aware that Kurald Galain darkness can be sensed by creatures of the realm, sometimes miles or hundreds of miles away.</li>
			</ul></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Malasul Gathol" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_HEAVY_PLATE_MALASUL_GATHOL">
		<description>
			<p>Made of thousands of tiny rings crafted out of a rare obsidian colored metal intertwined with strings of blackwood, and enchanted in a way that allows it to change its form, Malasul Gathol is a suit of armor which can shift into two distinct modes, either into a plate armor or into a shiny black chain link cloak.</p>
			<p><b>Shifting:</b> As a Bonus Action, the armor can shift into one of two forms. While in that form, you gain the following benefits:
			<ul>
				<li><b>Plate Armor:</b> You get the benefits of a +2 Mithral Armor, as well as a +5 bonus to Dexterity (Stealth) checks.</li>
				<li><b>Cloak:</b> You get your proficiency bonus added to any charisma skill check, but you no longer get any bonus to your armor class. While in this form, it only takes an action to don or doff the armor.</li>
			</ul></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">plate</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
			<set name="type" addition="plate">Armor</set>
			<set name="armor">Plate</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="armorClass">18</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_PLATE</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:armored:enhancement" value="2" bonus="enhancement"/>
			<stat name="stealth:misc" value="5" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Blight Shield" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_BLIGHT_SHIELD">
		<description>
			<p>Does not count towards attuned items count.</p>
			<p>Made of special alloy highly receptive to necromantic enchantment.</p>
			<p>The Magic Shield +2 has 3 charges and regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn. When you take damage from a creature within 5 feet of you while holding this shield, you can use your reaction to expend 1 of its charges to use the spell "Blight" on that creature. The spell does not emanate from you, instead from the shield itself.</p>
			<p>Constitution Saving Throw DC 18.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shield</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:shield" value="2" bonus="enhancement"/>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!--End:: Custom Armors for Book of the fallen -->
  
</elements>
