<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Book of the Fallen - Custom Feats</name>
		<description>
		Contains Custom Feats created specifically for the campaign &quot;Book of the Fallen&quot;.
		</description>
		<update version="1.0.4">
			<file name="botf-custom-items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/EliasKokkinos/umbraxakar/master/core/feats.xml"/>
		</update>
	</info>

	<!--Start:: Custom Feats for Book of the fallen -->
	<element name="Mark of Shadowthrone" type="Feat" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_FEAT_MOST">
		<description>
			<p>Shadows now bow to your will, for the Shadowthrone mark is upon your soul. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You can use the Hide action in dim light or darkness.</li>
				<li>Whenever you take the Hide action and successfully become undetected, you can move normally up to 30 feet before losing the benefits of being hidden.</li>
				<li>You can cast Duskwalk times and casting level equal to your Proficiency Bonus, without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can use the Hide action in dim light or darkness. Whenever you take the Hide action and successfully become undetected, you can move normally up to 30 feet before losing the benefits of being hidden.
			You can cast Shadow Walk times and casting level equal to your Proficiency Bonus, without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_BOTF_SPELL_SHADOWWALK" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Mistborn" type="Feat" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_FEAT_MIST">
		<description>
			<p>You have become Mistborn by the swallowing of a bead of Lerasium:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You can burn various metals which alter your physical and mental abilities. This ability is known as Allomancy and its secrets are closely guarded.</li>
				<li>You can burn steel 1d8 times (every short rest if you have access to salvageable steel. The steel must be non magical), without expending a spell slot.</li>				
				<li>You can burn iron 1d8 times (every short rest if you have access to salvageable steel. The iron must be non magical), without expending a spell slot.</li>				
				<li>You can burn pewter 1d4 times (every long rest if you have access to salvageable steel. The pewter must be non magical), without expending a spell slot.</li>				
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
			<ul>
				<li>You can burn various metals which alter your physical and mental abilities. This ability is known as Allomancy and its secrets are closely guarded.</li>
				<li>You can burn steel 1d8 times (every short rest if you have access to salvageable steel. The steel must be non magical), without expending a spell slot.</li>				
				<li>You can burn iron 1d8 times (every short rest if you have access to salvageable steel. The iron must be non magical), without expending a spell slot.</li>				
				<li>You can burn pewter 1d4 times (every long rest if you have access to salvageable steel. The pewter must be non magical), without expending a spell slot.</li>				
			</ul>
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_BOTF_SPELL_ALLOMANCYSTEEL" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_BOTF_SPELL_ALLOMANCYIRON" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_BOTF_SPELL_ALLOMANCYIRONSTEEL" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_BOTF_SPELL_ALLOMANCYPEWTER" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Silver-Tongued (Persuasion)" type="Feat" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_FEAT_SILVERTONGUED_PERSUASION">
		<description>
			<p>You develop your conversational skill to better deceive others. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
				<li>You gain proficiency in the Persuasion skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
				<li>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one attack with an attempt to persuade one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you that can see and hear you. Make a Charisma (Persuasion) check contested by the target’s Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, your movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks from the target and your attack rolls against it have advantage; both benefits last until the end of your next turn or until you use this ability on a different target. If your check fails, the target can’t be deceived by you in this way for 1 hour.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Attack">
			<description>You can attempt to persuade one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you that can see and hear you. Make a Charisma (Persuasion) check contested by the target’s Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, your movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks from the target and your attack rolls against it have advantage; both benefits last until the end of your next turn or until you use this ability on a different target. If your check fails, the target can’t be deceived by you in this way for 1 hour.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="charisma" value="1" />
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_PERSUASION" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Allomantic Charger" type="Feat" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_FEAT_ALLOMANTIC_CHARGER">
		<description>
			<p>When you use your Action to Dash or Jump using Allomancy, as a Bonus Action you can make one melee weapon Attack or Shove a creature with Advantage.<br />
			Additionally, if you:
			<ul>
				<li>Dash: move at least 10 feet in a straight line immediately before taking this Bonus Action</li>
				<li>Jump: move 10 feet before performing the Jump and land within reach of the target</li>
			</ul>
			you either gain a +5 bonus to the attack damage roll (if you make a melee attack and hit), or push the target up to 10 feet away from you (if you shove and you succeed).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you use your Action to Dash or Jump using Allomancy, as a Bonus Action you can make one melee weapon Attack or Shove a creature with Advantage.<br />
			Additionally, if you Dash and move move at least 10 feet in a straight line immediately before taking the Bonus Action, or if move 10 feet before Jumping and land within reach of the target, you either gain a +5 bonus to the attack damage roll, or push the target up to 10 feet away from you.
			</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!--End:: Custom Feats for Book of the fallen -->

</elements>
