<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Book of the Fallen - Custom Weapons</name>
		<description>
		Contains Custom Weapons created specifically for the campaign &quot;Book of the Fallen&quot;.
		</description>
			<file name="botf-custom-weapons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/EliasKokkinos/umbraxakar/master/core/weapons.xml"/>
		</update>
	</info>

	<!--Start:: Custom Weapons for Book of the fallen -->
	<element name="Dragnipur" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_MAGIC_ITEM_DRAGNIPUR">
		<description>
			<p>The black blade of this sword is crafted from a mysterious arcane alloy which seems to only reflect moonlight. Its blade is wider than a typical sword of its type, with a pronounced medial ridge. It's lightness in unparallel. 
        Sideswept golden quillons protect the hand, while an ornate vine shaped forward basket surrounds a dull part of the blade.			</p>
			<br/>
			<p>You gain the following benefits when attuned to Dragnipur:</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<ul>
					<li>You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. In addition, the weapon ignores resistance to slashing damage.</li>
					<li>When you attack a creature that has at least one head with this weapon and roll a 20 on the attack roll, you cut off one of the creature's heads. 
            The creature dies if it can't survive without the lost head. A creature is immune to this effect if it is immune to slashing damage, doesn't have or need a head, has legendary actions,           
            or the GM decides that the creature is too big for its head to be cut off with this weapon. Such a creature instead takes an extra 6d8 slashing damage from the hit.					</li>
					<li>When you hit a creature with an attack using this weapon, you can fill the target with unsettling dread: the target has disadvantage on the next saving throw it makes before the end of your next turn. 
            The creature ignores this effect if it's immune to the frightened condition. Once you use this property, you can't do so again until the next dusk.					</li>
					<li>You can see in magical darkness.</li>
					<li>You are immune to being frightned.</li>
					<li><em>Gift of Draconus.</em>Any creature slain by the sword can have their soul pulled into it. This is a punishment reserved for the most wretched creatures.</li>
					<li><em>Disheartening Strike.</em>When you hit a creature with an attack using this weapon, you can fill the target with unsettling dread: 
            the target has disadvantage on the next saving throw it makes before the end of your next turn. The creature ignores this effect if it's immune to the frightened condition. Once you use this property, 
            you can't do so again until the next dusk.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword that deals slashing damage">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Hammer of Hephaestus" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_HAMMER_OF_HEPHAESTUS">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_BLUDGEONING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_VERSATILE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_HAMMERS</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				<strong>
					<br/>
					<em>Lore:</em>
				</strong>The wielder is aware that Hephaestus is one of the many names of the god of Blacksmiths, Draconus.
			</p>
			<br/>
			<p>You gain the following benefits when attuned and wielding the Hammer of Hephaestus:</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<ul>
					<li>You have a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</li>
					<li>You may use you SPELL ATTACK BONUS instead of your ATTACK BONUS to strike with this weapon, to which you may also add the +2 bonus.</li>
					<li>The weapon is charged by the wielder's magic. Does an extra Proficiency Modifier x d10 Fire Damage after at least 1/3 of the casters spell slots are consumed in the last 10 minutes.</li>
					<li>When the wielder attunes with the hammer they are aware that if it is hit on the ground on its spike and the words "By the name of Hephaestus I seek entry" are called, something may happen.</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">warhammer, dwarf</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="type" addition="warhammer">Weapon</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="damage" type="bludgeoning">1d8</set>
			<set name="versatile">1d10</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Warhammer</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Glaive of the Sword" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_GLAIVE_OF_THE_SWORD">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_SLASHING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_HEAVY, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_REACH, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_TWOHANDED</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				<ul>
					<li>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</li>
					<li>When you hit, you add an additional 2d4 Necrotic Damage.</li>
					<li>Requires attunement (1 hour of meditation).</li>
					<li>This weapon has 6 charges and regains 1d4 + 2 expended charges daily at dusk. While holding this glaive, you can expend 1 or more of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it (Save DC 16):<br/>
		  - Mirror Image (1 charge)<br/>
		  - Phantom Steed (1 charge)<br/>
		  - Speak with Dead (1 charge)<br/>
		  - Spirit Guardians (2 charges)</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				<strong><em>Spectral Warrior:</em></strong>Once on each of your turns, when you hit a creature with this Glaive, you can choose to summon a Spectral Warrior from the weapon. Until the start of your next turn, that creature is haunted by the warrior. While haunted, a creature has disadvantage on weapon attacks against you.
			</p>
			<p>
				<strong><em>Spectral Phalanx:</em></strong>You can use an action while holding this glaive to expend 3 of its charges and point it forward commandingly. Four spectral, glaive-wielding warriors appear in line with you and march in a 25-foot-by-50(max)-foot  line in a direction you choose. You can choose to traverse less than 50 feet. During the attack you become spectral as well, and you can select how many of the four spectral warriors stand to the left and your right, essentially determining you position in the phalanx.  This movement does not count towards your allotted movement in a given round, and can only be initiated if an enemy will be affected during the march. As a spectral entity you can pass through enemies, but not stop in their occupied area, and solid objects spanning less that a continuous 3 feet. This restriction does not apply for the summoned spectral warriors.<br/>
	  Any creature within that line’s area must make a DC 16 Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 3d10 necrotic damage and 3d10 psychic damage and is affected by the weapon’s spectral warrior property. On a success, the creature takes half as much damage and isn’t affected by the spectral warriors.
	  Spectral Phalanx counts as a Level 1 spell for the purposes of the players turn, but does not consume a spell slot and cannot be countered or stopped by the normal means applying for a spell of that level.
			</p>
			<p>
				<br/><strong>Lore:</strong>
	  The Glaive is believed to have been crafted by the God Hephaestus himself, and enchanted by the master enchanter Samuel Yellin.				<br/>
	  When first attuned to the Glaive the bearer is made aware that the weapon and others of its kind where carried by some of the men in the company known as Dassem's Sword and in a vision can see soldiers saluting.				<br/>
				<br/>
	  In the pommel something is written in a strange unknown language.	  
			</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE"/>
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTOM_STEED"/>
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD"/>
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS"/>
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">glaive</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="type" addition="glaive">Weapon</set>
			<set name="slot">twohand</set>
			<set name="damage" type="slashing">1d10</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Glaive</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE"/>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTOM_STEED"/>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD"/>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Matriarch's Kiss (Shortsword)" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_MATRIARCHS_KISS">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_PIERCING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_FINESSE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LIGHT, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				<ul>
					<li>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</li>
					<li>When you hit, you add an additional 1d6 Slashing + 1d6 Necrotic.</li>
					<li>Requires attunement.</li>
					<li>Causes Bleeding on failed Constitution savaving throw (DC 15).</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				<strong><em>Envelop in Mist:</em></strong>
				<ul>
					<li>While wielded in combat a magical mist envelops the bearer, providing them with an additional +2 AC.</li>
					<li>As a Reaction, mist surrounding the wielder thickens which causes any attacks targeting them to be taken with disadvantage until the start of their next turn. Can be used Prof. Bonus times per Long Rest.</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				<br/><strong>Bleeding Condition:<br/></strong>
	  Bleeding creatures must make a Constitution Saving Throw DC 14 at the end of their turns, or lose 18 (2d6) maximum hit points. A successful Const. save of DC 18 ends this condition. Multiple instances of bleeding do not stack. If a bleeding creature's maximum hit points becomes less than their current hit points, its current hit points are reduced to match the max. The target gains a level of exhaustion for every 1/5 of its original max hp lost this way. A DC 15 Wisdom (Medicine) check or magical healing will stop the bleeding. A long rest with food and water recovers all max hit points and all levels of bleeding exhaustion. Alternatively, Greater Restoration or a DC 18 Wisdom (Medicine) check may restore the max hit points, but not the exhaustion. 	  
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shortsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shortsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="damage" type="piercing">1d6</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Shortsword</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:misc" value="2"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Matriarch's Kiss (Longsword)" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_MATRIARCHS_KISS_LONGSWORD">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_SLASHING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_VERSATILE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				<ul>
					<li>You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</li>
					<li>When you hit, you add an additional 1d8 Piercing + 1d8 Necrotic.</li>
					<li>Requires attunement.</li>
					<li>Causes Bleeding on failed Constitution saving throw (DC 15).</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				<strong><em>Envelop in Mist:</em></strong>
				<ul>
					<li>While wielded in combat a magical mist envelops the bearer, providing them with an additional +2 AC.</li>
					<li>As a Reaction, mist surrounding the wielder thickens which causes any attacks targeting them to be taken with disadvantage until the start of their next turn. Can be used Prof. Bonus times per Long Rest.</li>
				</ul>
				<strong><em>Vampiric Blade:</em></strong>
				<ul>
					<li>The wielder of this sword recovers hitpoints equal to the necrotic damage dealt with each successful hit.</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				<br/><strong>Bleeding Condition:<br/></strong>
	  Bleeding creatures must make a Constitution Saving Throw DC 14 at the end of their turns, or lose 18 (2d6) maximum hit points. A successful Const. save of DC 18 ends this condition. Multiple instances of bleeding do not stack. If a bleeding creature's maximum hit points becomes less than their current hit points, its current hit points are reduced to match the max. The target gains a level of exhaustion for every 1/5 of its original max hp lost this way. A DC 15 Wisdom (Medicine) check or magical healing will stop the bleeding. A long rest with food and water recovers all max hit points and all levels of bleeding exhaustion. Alternatively, Greater Restoration or a DC 18 Wisdom (Medicine) check may restore the max hit points, but not the exhaustion. 	  
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">longsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="damage" type="slashing">1d8</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGSWORD</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:misc" value="2"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Crysknife" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_CRYSKNIFE">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_PIERCING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_FINESSE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LIGHT, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This dagger grants its wielder the following benefits:
				<ul>
					<li>+3d4 Psychic damage.</li>
					<li>Range when thrown: 30/90 ft</li>
					<li><b><i>Shifting Sands:</i></b>The weapon can appear in the owners hand when its command word is spoken (Free Action)</li>
					<li><b><i>Shai-Hulud Skin:</i></b>You can use your Reaction to turn your skin into a layered, string as mithral, brown skin that provides the brearer with 50 temporary HP. This effect ends when all the temporary HP are depleted or at the start of the bearer's next turn.</li>
					<li><b><i>Missionaria Protectiva:</i></b>There is a deep cultural recognition among people of the desert of this type of blade. They consider the acquisition of the blad as a consequence of fate and will treat the bearer with the utmost respect.</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dagger</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="range">30/90</set>
			<set name="damage" type="piercing">1d4</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_DAGGER</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Jolnir" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_STAFF_Jolnir">
		<description>
			<p>A Staff of Molten Lava gifted to the mage Darwin by the spirit of Jólnir, an Ascendant god of volcanoes.
				<ul>
					<li>The staff can be made to shine bright Sunlight in a 30ft radius, and dim light for an additional 30ft.</li>
					<li>When attuned, the bearer gains access to the Firebrand spell.</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_BOTF_SPELL_FIREBRAND"/>
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a Wizard or Sorcerer">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_BOTF_SPELL_FIREBRAND"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="The Leech" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_THE_LEECH">
		<description>
			<p>Does not count towards attuned items count.</p>
			<p>Made of special alloy highly receptive to necromantic enchantment.</p>
			<p>This fine blade is crafted from a strange black metal and seems to draw in blood if any touches its blade. You gain +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon</p>
			<p>When you hit a Small or larger living creature with this weapon, that creature takes an extra 2d8 necrotic damage and you regain hit points equal to half the amount of necrotic damage dealt in this way. Constructs, plants and undead creatures are immune to this necrotic damage.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Curse:</em></strong></p>
			<p class="indent">The sword is cursed, and becoming attuned to it extends the curse to you. As long as you remain cursed, you are unwilling to part with the sword, keeping it within reach at all times. You also have disadvantage on attack rolls with weapons other than this one, unless no foe is within 60 feet of you that you can see of hear. In addition, while you remain cursed, the number of HP you regain when healed my magical means (other than the sword's effect) is halved.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greatsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greatsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="The Rose" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_THE_ROSE">
		<description>
			<p>Does not count towards attuned items count.</p>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attach and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Oathkeeper:</em></strong></p>
			<p>While attuned to this weapon it's nearly impossible to lie, however you are recognized and respected by people. Reduce any deception rolls made while attuned by 10 to a minimum of 1. Add +5 to any persuasion rolls made while attuned.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Vorpal:</em></strong></p>
			<p>When you attack a creature that has at least one head with this weapon and roll a 20 on the attack roll, you cut off one of the creatures heads. The creature dies if it can't survive without the lost head. A creature is immune to this effect if it's immune to slashing damage, doesn't have or need a head, has legendary actions, of the GM decides that the creature is too big for its head to be cut off with this weapon. Such a creature instead takes an extra 6d8 Slashing damage from this hit.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Devastating Fury:</em></strong></p>
			<p>Against humanoid enemies with a Dexterity modifier of 2 and below (Dex 15), with a 19 on the attack roll you can break a limb if the enemy fails a Constitution Saving Throw DC 16. This will significantly lower their ability to defend and attack. A creature is immune to this effect if it'ss immune to Bludgeoning damage or has legenday actions.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greatsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greatsword</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="persuasion:misc" value="5" />
			<stat name="deception:misc" value="-10" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<!-- PENDING IN GAME ROLLS
	<element name="Staff of Promises" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_STAFF_OF_PROMISES">
		<description>
			<p>Does not count towards attuned items count.</p>
			<p>The staff seemingly posses a soul which can be speculated to be an amalgam of souls harvested or fed to it by its previous owners. It's obvious to anyone with considerable arcane skil to examine this artifact that attuning to this is liable to at the very least twist the psyche or even drive their mind into madness.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_BOTF_SPELL_FIREBRAND"/>
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a Spellcaster">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_BOTF_SPELL_FIREBRAND"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	-->

	<element name="Stinger (light)" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_STINGER_LIGHT">
		<description>
			<p>Does not count towards attuned items count.</p>
			<p>The weapon is a feat of engineering and magic, as it is entirely mechanical in operation, but augments its attacks with magic. You gain +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When you hit an undead creature with an attack using this weapon, the attack deals an extra 1d8 necrotic damage, and the creature has disadvantage on Saving Throws and is vulnerable against necromantic spells.</p>
			<p>The repeating crossbow (whether heavy or light) holds 15 crossbow bolts. As long as it holds bolts, you can reload it by pulling the reloading level (Free Action). Loading a new case of 15 bolts is a Full-round Action that provokes Attacks of Opportunity. You can fire a repeating crossbow with one hand or with one in each hand in the same manner as you would a normal crossbow of the same size. However, you must fire the weapon with two hands in order to use the loading lever, and you must use two hands to load a new case of bolts.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="light, repeating">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LIGHT,ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_CROSSBOWS,ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_AMMUNITION</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="The Punisher" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_THE_PUNISHER">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_BLUDGEONING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_VERSATILE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_HAMMERS</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Does not count towards attuned items count.</p>
			<p>MAde of special alloy highly receptive to the enchantments associated with the effects listed in the table below.</p>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. You attack with advantage against heavily armored foes or creatures with scales and natural armor.</p>
			<p>The might of this hammer changes to reflect your nature, using your innermost morality to overpower those that would oppose you. A creature hit by te hammer takes an extra 1d8 damage for each hald of your alignment, for a total of 2d8 extra damage. The damage type(s) are determined by their associated alignments, as shown below:</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Alignment 1</td><td>Damage Type 1</td><td>Alignment 2</td><td>Damage Type 2</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Lawful</td><td>Thunder</td><td>Good</td><td>Radiant</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Neutral</td><td>Force</td><td>Neutral</td><td>Force</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Chaotic</td><td>Fire</td><td>Evil</td><td>Necrotic</td></tr>
			</table>
			<p>You can choose to surpress one or both halves of your alignment each time you hit a target with the hammer (no action required). When you do, the creature doesn't take the surpressed alignment's damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">warhammer, dwarf</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any hammer">Weapon</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="damage" type="bludgeoning">1d8</set>
			<set name="versatile">1d10</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Warhammer</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Mothers Dawn" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_MOTHERS_DAWN">
		<description>
			<p>This glorious sword leaves ribbons of light trailing in the wake of the blade. Some who have witnessed it say that the ribbons of light appear to reveal a painting of a sunrise. 
			This weapon deals radiant damage instead of piercing damage. Once per turn, when you attack with this weapon while prone, you can rise to your feet and gain advantage on the attack.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shortsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shortsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Shortsword</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Mothers Dusk" type="Magic Item" source="Book of the Fallen" id="ID_BOTF_CUSTOM_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_MOTHERS_DUSK">
		<description>
			<p>This shrouded blade is cast in a black hue and appears to have stars dimly shining from within. Some say that an image of a sunset can be seen in the dark shadows that follow the blade’s edge. 
			This weapon deals kuralt galain damage instead of piercing damage. Once per turn, when you attack with this weapon while dim light, darkness or kuralt galain, you gain advantage on the attack, 
			and if you hit, the target is knocked prone.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shortsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shortsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Shortsword</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!--End:: Custom Weapons for Book of the fallen -->
  
</elements>
